What's the point of having a stairway
when no one ever uses it?
It's been a long time since you
last came here to the seabed,
problem child of the Great Hall.
That was a long time ago, Alaira.
I wonder about that.
It sounds like you've been
stirring up trouble again.
I heard about your new apprentice.
Already? Word travels fast.
Does she have the connection you're looking for?
The Brimmed Caps?
No one's used forbidden magic in four years.
She's an important lead.
It's not about that.
And she hasn't taken her tests,
so she's not my official apprentice yet.
Oh, she hasn't?
It's too soon.
It's a bad time for it, too.
Oh, of course.
At this time of year, the Dadah Range,
where the test takes place...
They'll be at their highest elevation.
I wouldn't dream of putting
someone through that test now.
It could get them killed.
Hey, Agott.
Are you sure I should do this?
Master Qifrey isn't even here...
You'll be doing it alone
when you take it anyways.
B-But I only just got here!
I passed the test when I was ten.
We all have to pass it
to become apprentices,
so you're in the same boat we were.
I see...
The first test is "Consent of the Crown."
You can only take three contraptions
and your components.
You have to reach the summit of the
Dadah Range purely on your own power,
and pick the Diadem Herb
that grows there.
The Guidance Orb that points
the way to your destination,
and the Vapor Bubble for drinking water...
That's probably all you can use right now.
Go on, then.
Um... and...
Could I have the shoes?
Shoes?
Those shoes are  too, right?
Yours and Master Qifrey's...
I saw the soles glow while
you were flying around.
So I thought... maybe...
you could lend me a pair?
That's too much, right?!
Forget I said it!
For you to borrow.
So just...
Thank you!
Get going already!
I forgot to mention it, but you
only get to take this test once.
If you fail, you'll never be allowed
to be Master Qifrey's apprentice.
You'll have to leave the atelier, too.
I'm suddenly terrified...
But I've got to give it my best!
No turning back now!
How do I use the Guidance Orb, anyway?
Does it want me to go this way?
Okay!
I can handle a little mountain-climbing!
I can do it!
Agott said she passed when she was ten!
If she could do it at ten...
I can... also...
No way.
You mean...
This is the Dadah Range?
The Guidance Orb is pointing up.
It's up there, then.
I didn't realize they'd be floating.
Ta-da!
The shoes I borrowed from Agott!
Fly!
Huh?
The Casting Seal is split between
the right and left foot.
Make sure they're perfectly aligned...
Wow! I'm really floating!
Master Qifrey was right.
I'm like a newborn foal stumbling around.
But...
I flew.
Flying can take me to
the summit in no time!
All right...
I can do this!
You'll get used to it and be
running around freely in no time.
Get used to it. Get used to it.
Here's the application.
Please process it.
Right.
Thotrey. Number 12.
If you'd live in the Great Hall, you wouldn't have to travel so far for every little thing.
Let's see... number 12, number 12...
Oh, here it is.
You could bring your apprentices, too.
I don't see the box, sir!
The Great Hall is
the witches' stronghold.
There's one in the back, right?
It has everything we need.
Which is why I come here
when I need things.
There it is! Here we go!
Here you are.
Thank you.
Sir, is this for that Outsider—
Your hatred of the Great Hall runs deep, I see.
Thotrey!
I'm sorry!
Keep an eye on those apprentices of yours.
You never know what children that age
might get up to without adults around.
I think I'm keeping my balance
better than before!
Maybe now I can go a little higher...
A brushbuddy! I've never seen one before!
The shoes are caked with mud...
The Casting Seal came off?!
No way! Because I wiped it?
Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no!
I know! I'll just draw it back on!
The Conjuring Ink spilled in my bag...
What do I do?
Is it all over?
Huh?
Hey, Agott. Have you seen Coco?
It's about time for dinner.
Coco's not here.
She went to the Dadah Range for her test.
What?! By herself?!
But she just got to the atelier!
Why didn't you stop her?
C'mon, Agott!
Most people take the test
before coming here, right?
Y-Yes, but...
If she can't pass a test that simple,
she shouldn't be an apprentice.
I hate people who can't do what I can.
I gain no benefit being around them.
Especially Outsiders.
Don't worry. She'll fail and
come back soon enough.
The Dadah Range is at its
highest this time of year.
She won't be able to fly that high
with just my Sylph Shoes.
She doesn't even know the rules
or realize how dangerous this is.
I don't want someone
like that in our world.
Tetia, are you not going to eat?
I am, but...
I feel kinda... down.
Going for more.
Am I seriously the only one who's worried?!
There's nothing to do but wait
for Master Qifrey regardless.
It's no use.
I tried drawing it back on
with what little ink I had left,
but I can't even float now.
The ink soaks in and dilutes because it's still wet.
If I drew it directly on the soles of my feet...
No! Magic drawn onto the body is forbidden.
I don't know what kind of magic
I should use at a time like this.
I guess Agott was right.
Anyone can draw a spell, but that
doesn't mean they'll be good at it.
I guess you have to be a special
kind of person to be a witch after all.
They've all been drawing spells
since they were children.
It's not something I could ever...
Nice and straight.
I had no idea this village had
such a skilled craftsman.
This is real magic.
I have it...
I have my own magic!
If I let a little water
soak in and dilute it...
The mud's dried on my wet cape
and made it a little stiff.
I think I can draw on it like this.
It's natural to have unsteady hands
when you're learning to use a new tool.
Then I'll swap it for a tool I'm used to.
My fingers begin to dance of their own accord.
Freely.
There!
Morning, brushbuddy!
You've made yourself at home, haven't you?
It's a pretty ugly Casting Seal, isn't it?
To draw one properly,
the sigil needs to be centered,
and the signs are supposed to be uniform.
He taught me that if the signs aren't balanced,
it can put too much energy
into one direction.
I wanted to see what would happen
if I made one long on purpose!
I'm not sure if it'll work, though.
You want to come, too?
Really? Hold on tight, then.
I'm closing the ring.
What? What's happening?!
Did I get the sign's direction wrong?!
I did it!
I'm flying with my own spell!
A real cloak of flight...
It's like a dream!
I never thought helping Mom
would help me learn magic...
But the Diadem Herb is higher than this!
The Diadem Herb!
Mom...
Wait for me, Mom!
I'll take responsibility for what I've done!
So Coco went to the Dadah Range
to take the test for herself?!
That's too dangerous!
I have to go save her!
But she'll fail if you interrupt her!
It was too soon for her to take the test anyway.
She hasn't been living around magic
her whole life like we have.
If anything were to happen to Coco...
She wouldn't be the only loss suffered.
There.
Eh?
Coco!
Thank goodness!
Coco! You're safe!
I was so totally, totally worried about you!
Agott!
I got the "Consent of the Crown."
This is the proof I need, right?
Coco.
It's extremely dangerous to cast spells
without the proper preparation
and fundamental knowledge.
I thought you'd learned that already.
You could easily have died back there.
Never do anything like that again.
I'm sorry, Master Qifrey.
Besides, you didn't need to put yourself
in danger to prove anything.
You're already my apprentice.
This is...
The proof that you're a witch.
It's both our pride
and a shackle that rests atop our head
so we don't abuse our magic.
As long as you wear it,
don't forget its weight.
The pointed cap is watching your magic.
Take good care of it.
Okay!
All right. Let's go back up.
Guess we'd better eat first!
Take a bath, too.
The seed has sprouted.